Wolf, Benjamin Additional Papers 5511
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Benjamin Wolf Additional Papers
1966-1973
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wolf, Benjamin
5511
5.5 cubic feet
5.5 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Arbitration files, hearing transcripts, opinions, correspondence and notes of the impartial arbitrator Benjamin Wolf.
5658203
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
CB, June 06, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 14, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Arbitrator, labor mediator and attorney; visiting professor, New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University. Wolf served as permanent arbitrator between the New York City Board of Education and the United Federation of Teachers; New York City and the American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME); the New York City Off-Track Betting Corp. and AFSCME; New York State and AFSCME; the State University of New York and the Senate Professional Association; A. Goodman and the American Bakery and Confectionery Workers' Union; and between the Simmons Company and the Upholsterers International Union. Wolf also served as impartial chairman for American Airlines and the Transport Workers Union of America; the men's shirt industry and the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; and the Brooklyn Union Gas Company and the Transport Workers Union of America.
Born May 6, 1909. Attended Cornell University (B.A. 1930; LL.B. 1932).
Formerly labor mediator, New York State Board of Meidation; labor relations examiner, N.Y.S. Labor Relations Board.
Affiliated with National Academy of Arbitrators (board of governors 1971-; regional chairman 1967-1968); Industrial Relations Research Association; Society for Professionals in Dispute Resolution; New York Bar Association. On rosters of American Arbitration Association, Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, National Mediation Board, New York State Board of Mediation, New Jersey State Board of Mediation, New York Public Employment Relations Board, New Jersey Public Employment Relations Commission.
Arbitrator under contract for N.Y. City Board of Education and UFT; City of New York and District Council 37; OTB and DC37; N.Y. State and Council 82, AFSCME: State University of New York and Senate Professional Association; Metropolitan New York Milk Industry and IBT; New Rochelle Board of Education and UFT; A. Goodman & Sons and BCWU; Metropolitan Association of Optical Wholesalers and IUE; Simons Co. and Local 420, UIU.
Impartial Chairman; American Airlines and TWU, Men's Shirt Industry and ACWA; Brooklyn Union Gas and TWU; Williams Press and Pressmen's Union; Hiring Hall & Club Employees Union (Local 16); Westchester County Laundry Board of Trade and Local 335 IBT: Rochdale Village, Inc. and Local 90 Public Service Union; Ossining Board of Education and Ossining Teachers Association; Schwartz Laboratories, Inc. and Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers; Ross Oil Term. Corp., Howard Fuel Corp. & Local 365 UAW.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6433: Benjamin H. Wolf Collections 5305: Benjamin H. Wolf Papers 5477: Benjamin Wolf Papers 5511: Benjamin Wolf Additional Papers 5539: Benjamin H. Wolf Additional Arbitration Files
Wolf, Benjamin H.,1909-
5658203
- 5305/7 (series 7)-American Airlines cases. Arranged in chronological order. This series includes statements of grievances, disposition of grievances, System Board of Adjustment, Division II opinions, bills, and notes. 1966-1973.. (Box 1)
  - American Airlines (AA) vs. H.E. Stamper, Local 514, TWU, 3/1/66, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    #S-6-68 Decision - Overtime
  - AA vs. M.D. Watkins, Local 514, TWU, 8/8/67, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    #M-187-67 Decision - Overtime, Assignment of Jobs
  - AA vs. K.D. Poor, Local 514, TWU, 8/7/67, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    #S-180-67 Decision - Overtime
  - AA vs. R.M. Baker, Local 514, TWU, 4/24/68, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    #S-10-68 Decision - Overtime
  - AA vs. W.A. Jones, Local 514, TWU, 10/24/68, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    #S-17-68 Decision - Overtime, Assignment of Jobs
  - AA vs. T. Birmingham, Local 514, TWU, 9/25/69, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    #M-131-68 Decision - Seniority, Grievance Procedure
  - AA vs. K.C. Harris, Local 512, TWU, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    #M-216-68 Decision - Transfers, Contracting Out
  - AA vs. W.W. Beaver, TWU, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    #M-1-69; #M-43-69 Decision - Overtime
  - AA vs. G. Ludwig & J. Santos, Local 501, TWU, 3/25/70, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    #M-68-183, 254, 314, 331 Decision - Overtime, Classification of Jobs
  - AA vs. W.W. Berner, Local 514, TWU, 8/12/70, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    #M-155-69, #M-193-69 Decision - Overtime, Assignment of Jobs
  - AA vs. TWU (29d Protest), 10/21/71, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    #M-246-68 Decision - Job Assignments
  - AA vs. T.L. Corbin, Local 510, TWU, 11/20/70, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    #M-17-70, #M-87-70 Decision - Assignment
  - AA vs. Local 550, TWU, Airline Stewards & Stewardesses Assn., 11/23/70, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    #70-585 Decision - Strike, Layoff
  - AA vs. Local 501, R.L. Powers, TWU, 12/7/70, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    #M-182-70, 220-69, 327-69, 328-69 Decision - Job Assignments, Overtime
  - AA vs. B.T. Dunsfield, Local 513, TWU, 12/9/70, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    #M-66-70, #M-289-70 Decision - Overtime
  - AA vs. E. Garca, Local 502, TWU, 12/10/70, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    #M-143, M-338 Decision - Job Assignment, Absences
  - AA vs. Cotter, Cintolo, Mitchell, Local 507, TWU, 12/28/70, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    #M-324-69 Decision - Overtime, Job Classification
  - AA vs. J. Ludwig, S. Shell, Local 512, TWU, 1/22/71, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    #M-83-71, S-68-71A Decision - Assignment of Jobs, Layoff
  - AA vs. W. Goodsell, E. Lee, Local 514, TWU, 1/11/71, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    #M-159-69, M-102-70, M-103-70 Decision - Assignment of Jobs
- 5305/7 (series 7)-American Airlines cases. Arranged in chronological order. This series includes statements of grievances, disposition of grievances, System Board of Adjustment, Division II opinions, bills, and notes. 1966-1973.. (Box 2)
  - AA vs. E. Lawhorn, L/ Ott, C. Carson, Local 514, TWU, 1/20/71, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    #S-13-69, S-14-69, S-15-69 Decision - Assignment of Jobs
  - AA vs. Radford, Rott, Towtham, Tomaso, Local 505, TWU, 2/5/71, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    #M-98-70, M-99-70, M-328-69, M-385-70 Decision - Bidding, Assignment of Jobs, Overtime
  - AA vs. Local 514, TWU, 4/2/71, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    #M-238-69, M-60-70, M63-70, M126-70, M-134-70, M147, M-299, M300 Decision - Assignment of Jobs, Overtime, Transfers
  - AA vs. Local 513, TWU, 5/18/71, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    #M-384-70, M-19-71, M-102-71 Decision - Overtime, Bargaining Unit
  - AA vs. Local 514, TWU, 5/18/71, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    #M-322-70, M-323, M-324, M-325, M-326, M-327, M-329 Decision - Overtime, Bargaining Unit
  - AA vs. Local 501, TWU, 6/24/71, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    #M-305-70, M-378, M-405, M-407 Decision - Contracting Out, Termination of Employment
  - AA vs. Local 501, TWU, 8/17/71, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    #S-17-70. S-92, S-110, S-111 Decision - Assignment of Jobs
  - AA vs. Local 541, TWU, 8/18/71, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    #M-355-70 Decision - Seniority, Demotion
  - AA vs. Local 510, TWU, 9/15/71, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    #M-421-70, M-95, M-96, M-129 Decision - Assignment of Jobs, Layoff, Overtime, Transfers
  - AA vs. Local 514, TWU, 10/13/71, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    #M-399-70 Decision - Assignment of Jobs
  - AA vs. Local 512, TWU, 10/19/71 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    #M-317-70, M-347, M-380, M-33-71, M-271, M-272, M-273 Decision - Assignment of Jobs
  - AA vs. Local 502, TWU, 10/20/71, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    #S-104-70, M-256-70, M-399, M-58-71 Decision - Sub-Contracting
  - AA vs. Local 513, TWU, 11/3/71, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    #S-114-70, M-283-71, M-410-71 Decision - Overtime, Assignment of Jobs
  - AA vs. Local 501, TWU, 11/29/71, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    #M-182-70, M-381-71 Decision - Assignment of Jobs, Sub-Contracting
  - AA vs. Local 512, TWU, 11/29/71, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    #M-219-70, M-346-70, M-83-71 Decision - Seniority, Assignment of Jobs
  - AA vs. R.A. Leger, TWU, 12/14/71, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    #M-250-69 Rates of Pay
- 5305/7 (series 7)-American Airlines cases. Arranged in chronological order. This series includes statements of grievances, disposition of grievances, System Board of Adjustment, Division II opinions, bills, and notes. 1966-1973.. (Box 3)
  - AA vs. TWU, 1/72, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - AA vs. Local 512, TWU, 12/8/72, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    #M-157, M-159, M-146 Decision - Assignment of Jobs, Overtime
  - AA vs. Local 501, TWU, 5/1/72, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    #M-386-70, S-68-71 Decision - classification of Jobs, Contracting Out
  - AA vs. Local 514, TWU, 5/17/72, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    #M-243-71, Decision - Assignment of Jobs
  - AA vs. Local 514, TWU, 5/18/72 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - AA vs. Local 514, TWU, 5/30/72, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    #M-211-71 M-237-72, M-354-71, S-74-71 Decision - Overtime, Assignment of Jobs
  - AA vs. Local 512, TWU, 6/6/72, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    #M-93-72, M-94-72, M-172-72 Decision - Transfers, Seniority, Assignment of Jobs
  - AA vs. Local, TWU, 6/8/72, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    #M-6-70, M-50-72 Decision - Transfer, Assignment of Jobs, Rates of Pay
  - AA vs. Local 514, TWU, 8/4/72, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    #M-243-71, M-592-72 Decision - Assignment of Jobs, Classification of Jobs
  - AA vs. Local 502, TWU, 9/15/72, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    #M-392-72, S-94-72 Decision - Seniority, Contracting Out, Assignment of Jobs
  - AA vs. TWU, 9/30/72, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    #M-93-72, M-296-72 Decision - Reduction In Force, Seniority, Overtime
  - AA vs. TWU, 4/13/73, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    #M-460-71 Decision - Seniority, Transfer
- 5305/8 (series 8)-Hearing transcripts.. (Box 4)
  - City of New York (Department of Social Services) vs. Local 1549, AFSCME, District Council 37, 4/23/68, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    [Folder is numberless] Hearing Transcripts
- 5305/8 (series 8)-Hearing transcripts.. (Box 5)
  - Cedar Ridge High School - Before Benjamin H. Wolf, 12/17/69, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Hearing Transcript
  - Alatex, Inc. vs. Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 9/12/72, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Anheuser-Busch, Inc. vs. Joint Local Executive Board of New Jersey, 10/24/72, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Board of Education, City of New York vs. UFT, 11/14/72, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Board of Education, Half Hollow Hills Central School District #5 vs. Half Hollow Hills Teachers Association, 1/24/73, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Bay Shore Classroom Teachers Association vs. Union Free School District #1, Town of Islip, 1/29/73, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Container Corporation of America vs. United Paper Workers International Union, Local 520, 1/30/73, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- 5305/8 (series 8)-Decisions, notes, transcripts. Includes "J" series numbered 1-108 - Special Classification Appeals Board. Transcripts and related documents.. (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous decisions, notes, transcripts, etc. (Box 6, Folder All)
    Includes "J" series numbered 1-108: Special Classification Appeals Board. Transcripts and related documents.
- 5305/8 (series 8)-Decisions, notes, transcripts. Includes "J" series numbered 1-108 - Special Classification Appeals Board. Transcripts and related documents.. (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous decisions, notes, transcripts, etc. (Box 7, Folder All)
- 5305/8 (series 8)-Opinions, correspondence, publications and notes.. (Box 8)
  - Additional Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder All)
    Contains opinions, correspondence, publications, and notes.
- 5305/8 (series 8)-Opinions, correspondence, publications and notes.. (Box 9)
  - Additional Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder All)
- 5305/8 (series 8)-Opinions, correspondence, publications and notes.. (Box 10)
  - Additional Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder All)
- Opinions, correspondence, publications and notes.. (Box 11)
  - Additional Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder All)